<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <p>
    This Implementation Guide specifies profiles on the FHIR <a href="{{site.data.fhir.path}}device.html">Device</a>, <a href="{{site.data.fhir.path}}devicemetric.html">DeviceMetric</a>, and <a href="{{site.data.fhir.path}}observation.html">Observation</a> resources.
    Each profile defines constraints, extensions, and terminology requirements for an implementation that claims conformance to this guide.
  </p>
  <div class="clearfix">
    <img src="PoCD_Profiles.png" alt="PoCD Profiles" style="float:right" />
    <p>
      A point-of-care device model is made of multiple resource instances	and the relationships between them.
      The following diagram shows the FHIR resource profiles (blue) and references to other profiles or FHIR core resources (white).
    </p>
  </div>
  <a name="1"></a>
  <h3>Device Profiles and Extensions</h3>
  <table class="table-striped" style="width:100%">
    <col style="width:40%" />
    <col style="width:60%" />
    <tr>
      <td>
        <a href="StructureDefinition-MdsDevice.html">MDS Device profile</a>
      </td>
      <td>
        <p>StructureDefinition for Device resources that represent a Medical Device System (MDS). This is the top-level resource in the hierarchical model of a Point-of-Care device.</p>
      </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>
        <a href="StructureDefinition-VmdDevice.html">VMD Device profile</a>
      </td>
      <td>
        <p>StructureDefinition for Device resources that represent Virtual Medical Devices (VMD). These are medical-related subsystems in the hierarchical model of a Point-of-Care device.</p>
      </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>
        <a href="StructureDefinition-ChannelDevice.html">Channel Device profile</a>
      </td>
      <td>
        <p>StructureDefinition for Device resources that represent Channels, which are used for grouping metrics together.</p>
      </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>
        <a href="StructureDefinition-device-instance.html">Device Instance extension</a>
      </td>
      <td>
        <p>StructureDefinition that adds an instance number to Device.</p>
      </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>
        <a href="StructureDefinition-approved-jurisdictions.html">Approved Jurisdictions extension</a>
      </td>
      <td>
        <p>StructureDefinition that adds approved jurisdictions to a Device.</p>
      </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>
        <a href="StructureDefinition-operator.html">Operator extension</a>
      </td>
      <td>
        <p>StructureDefinition that adds an operator to a Device.</p>
      </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>
        <a href="StructureDefinition-operating-hours.html">Operating hours extension</a>
      </td>
      <td>
        <p>StructureDefinition that adds operating hours to a Device.</p>
      </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>
        <a href="StructureDefinition-operating-cycles.html">Operating cycles extension</a>
      </td>
      <td>
        <p>StructureDefinition that adds operating cycles to a Device.</p>
      </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>
        <a href="StructureDefinition-operating-mode.html">Operating mode extension</a>
      </td>
      <td>
        <p>StructureDefinition that adds an operating mode to a Device.</p>
      </td>
    </tr>
  </table>
  <a name="2"></a>
  <h3>DeviceMetric Profiles and Extensions</h3>
  <table class="table-striped" style="width:100%">
    <col style="width:40%" />
    <col style="width:60%" />
    <tr>
      <td>
        <a href="StructureDefinition-NumericDeviceMetric.html">Numeric DeviceMetric profile</a>
      </td>
      <td>
        <p>StructureDefinition for DeviceMetric resources that represent numerical measurements, calculations, or settings characteristics and capabilities.</p>
      </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>
        <a href="StructureDefinition-EnumerationDeviceMetric.html">Enumeration DeviceMetric profile</a>
      </td>
      <td>
        <p>StructureDefinition for DeviceMetric resources that represent coded or text status, annotations, or settings characteristics and capabilities.</p>
      </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>
        <a href="StructureDefinition-SampleArrayDeviceMetric.html">Sample Array DeviceMetric profile</a>
      </td>
      <td>
        <p>StructureDefinition for DeviceMetric resources that represent real-time waveforms or wave snippets characteristics and capabilities.</p>
      </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>
        <a href="StructureDefinition-relation.html">Relation extension</a>
      </td>
      <td>
        <p>StructureDefinition that adds relations to a DeviceMetric.</p>
      </td>
    </tr>
  </table>
  <a name="3"></a>
  <h3>Observation Profiles and Extensions</h3>
  <table class="table-striped" style="width:100%">
    <col style="width:40%" />
    <col style="width:60%" />
    <tr>
      <td>
        <a href="StructureDefinition-NumericObservation.html">Numeric Observation profile</a>
      </td>
      <td>
        <p>StructureDefinition for Observation resources that represent numerical measurements, calculations, or settings.</p>
      </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>
        <a href="StructureDefinition-CompoundNumericObservation.html">Compound Numeric Observation profile</a>
      </td>
      <td>
        <p>StructureDefinition for Observation resources that represent numerical measurements, calculations, or settings with multiple components.</p>
      </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>
        <a href="StructureDefinition-EnumerationObservation.html">Enumeration Observation profile</a>
      </td>
      <td>
        <p>StructureDefinition for Observation resources that represent coded or text status, annotations, or settings.</p>
      </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>
        <a href="StructureDefinition-SampleArrayObservation.html">Sample Array Observation profile</a>
      </td>
      <td>
        <p>StructureDefinition for Observation resources that represent real-time waveforms or wave snippets.</p>
      </td>
    </tr>
  </table>
</div>